# ALAINA J. HICKS

Chicago, IL 60628

Phone: 312.772.2691 | Email: ajhicks0816@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/alainajhicks | GitHub: https://github.com/ayejayhicks |

Portfolio: https://ayejayhicks.github.io/responsiveportfolio/

### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer, Project and program management professional with proven establishment of valued partnerships. Highly creative in development, support, and implementation of positive objectives in community organizations. Dedicated work ethic and service-oriented work experience within a purpose driven environment.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Skills:** HTML, CSS, Git, JavaScript, jQuery, MongoDB, MySQL Database, Visual Studio, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars, Microsoft Office Suite,

### **PROJECTS**

# Hungry Hangry Hippo | <a href="https://github.com/spicyJackrabbits/theFoodApp">https://github.com/spicyJackrabbits/theFoodApp</a> <a href="https://spicyjackrabbits.github.io/theFoodApp/">https://spicyjackrabbits.github.io/theFoodApp/</a>

- The goal of our application is to make the lives of Hungry and Hangry people easier. When a user goes to our website, they are presented with 2 questions:
  - o 1). Are you Hangry or Hungry?
  - o 2). What are you craving? Depending on the response our application returns to the user either 1 restaurant or 5 local restaurants near them.
- Application development and front end design
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS

# HomeGrown | https://github.com/caitie-gorham/project-2

https://homegrown-app-grizzlies.herokuapp.com/

- HomeGrown is a house plant based application that helps new plant owners learn about the top house plants and their basic needs.
- Application development and back end design
- Node.js, Express.js, Express-Handlebars, Express-Session, Sequelize, MySQ12, SQL Workbench, Path

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Employee 2016 – 2018
Marriott Brands Mount Juliet, TN

Provided excellent customer service to all hotel guests. Welcomes and acknowledges all guests according to company standards; anticipates and addresses guest service needs. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- Counted and secured bank. Processed all payment types, adjustment vouchers, paid-outs, correction vouchers, and miscellaneous charges.
- Communicated effectively with other Courtyard Mount Juliet departments, and associates

- Organized, confirmed, processed, and conducted all guest check-ins/check-outs, room reservations, requests, changes, and cancellations; trained new employees on FOSSE computer system.
- Identified and explained room features to guests; supply guests with directions and information regarding property amenities, services, and hours of operation, and local areas of interest.

Employee
Rutherford County Schools
Bleckley County Schools
Dublin City Schools

2011 – 2018 Murfreesboro, TN Cochran, GA Dublin, GA

Developed and executed lesson plans featuring age-appropriate activities geared toward stimulating the interests of children. Cultivated a warm supportive environment for developing the emotional and social growth of students.

Key Accomplishments:

- Managed a structured, stimulating classroom with responsibility in all areas of teaching, assessment, behavior modification and coordination of academic and social activities.
- Planned, developed and instituted educational activities that promoted quality teaching which corresponded with state standards.

**Employee Girl Scouts of Middle Tennessee** 

2006 – 2010

Nashville, TN

Successfully delivered a strong commitment in membership growth and retention, which resulted in the **Presidents' Award** for two consecutive fiscal years (2008–2009 & 2009–2010) based on increased membership and family contributions for the 1<sup>st</sup> time in individually assigned territory, Coffee and Moore counties.

Key Accomplishments:

- Extended 1300+ memberships from a combination of six counties within Middle Tennessee in 2010.
- Directly impacted Family Contribution program donations with \$1100+ in monetary donations.
- Collaborated with Membership Managers to support new fundraising campaigns; developed Project L.E.A.D training curriculum to award the Girl Scout experience to urban and rural areas of Middle Tennessee.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bootcamp Certificate:** Full Stack Web Development

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Progressive Web Apps, Agile Methodology, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handelbars.js, Git & React.js.

Degree or Certification: Georgia Tech | Atlanta, GA